LUKA BEVERIN

Minderbroedersstraat 8C, 3000 Leuven, Belgium $+32~495~85~36~04 \diamond lbeverin.sa@gmail.com$

Motivated, hard-working and responsible Data and Actuarial Scientist with significant experience in software packages such as SAS, R Studio and Python. Highly educated, possessing a Bachelor's and a Honours degree. Currently pursuing a Masters in Statistics and Data Science at the prestigious KU Leuven. Strengths lie in research, working with others and simplifying complex problems. Well versed in English and Serbian with an intermediate understanding of Afrikaans/Dutch

EDUCATION

Maragon Private School

2011-2015

Matric certificate

University of Pretoria, South Africa

2016-2018

BSc in Actuarial and Financial Mathematics

University of Pretoria, South Africa

2019

BSc (Hons) Mathematical Statistics.

KU Leuven, Belgium

Present - 2022

Master of Statistics and Data Science

PROJECTS

Estimating the Tail Index of a Truncated Extended Pareto Model

We proposed a truncated Extended Pareto Distribution estimator of the tail index through an exhaustive Markov Chain Monte Carlo algorithm. Our proposed estimator outperformed other estimation methods at different levels of truncation. This research report was completed with distinction during my Honours year at the University of Pretoria.

Topcoder - KPIs prediction challenge

Topcoder is a crowdsourcing company with an open global community of competitive programmers. Topcoder pays community members for their work on the projects and sells community services to corporate, mid-size, and small-business clients. The challenge was to build and develop an algorithm that can analyze historical data and predict 5 separate key performance indicators (KPIs) on the radio access networks (RAN), up to 2 hours in advance with 85% accuracy. For this challenge I implemented a Long short-term memory (LSTM) network and placed 2nd overall.

TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

Software & Tools

Python, SAS, R studio, SQL, MS Office, Latex

WORK EXPERIENCE

Day1 Health (Pty) Ltd

January 2017 to February 2017

Internship

· I worked for Day1 Health on a voluntary basis in order to gain knowledge and insight about the medical aid business environment. Day to day tasks involved drafting product brochures, product comparisons, systems training sessions and more.

Palisade

Internship

January 2018 to February 2018

· Palisade is a software company that specialises in decision analysis toolkits. My responsibilities have included interacting with the software on a daily basis, specifically @Risk, StatTools and NeuralTools. I have also familiarised myself with the customer relationship management (CRM) system whilst observing day-to-day business processes such as tele-communications, technical support and marketing to name but a few.

University of Pretoria

April 2019 to October 2019

Tutor and assistant

· I was a tutor for first year level statistics at a university level. I presented practical Excel sessions to students, which included topics such as random sampling, ANOVA, hypothesis testing and more.

CERTIFICATIONS

Actuarial Society of South Africa (ASSA)

2015-2018

- · A103 Finance and Financial Reporting
- · A205 Financial Mathematics

SAS and University of Pretoria

2020

· SAS Academic Specilization in Statistical Learning

ONLINE CERTIFICATIONS

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

2019-present

Courses:

- · Machine Learning with Python
- · Data Analysis with Python
- · Databases and SQL for Data Science
- · Python for Data Science and AI
- · Applied Data Science Capstone
- · Data Science Methodology
- · Open Source tools for Data Science
- · What is Data Science?

DataCamp 2018-present

- · Introduction to Deep Learning in Python
- · Time Series analysis in Python
- · Credit Risk Modelling in R

PERSONAL TRAITS

I am a highly motivated and ambitious individual who is eager to learn new things.

I have the ability to work as an individual as well as in group.

LINKS

GitHub

· https://github.com/lukazambuca/Projects

LinkedIn

· https://www.linkedin.com/in/luka-beverin-663128188/

Writer at Data Driven Investor

2019-present
2020-present

 $\cdot\ https://www.datadriveninvestor.com/author/lbeverin/$